everything in your trading Journey does
not matter at all unless you know how to
read technical analysis correctly if you
don't you simply will not make any money
in your trading career at all now I know
you heard different fors you can do
Market sentiment you can do news trading
fundamentals you can do bar candles all
this different type of stuff but
honestly all that stuff is way too
unpredictable technical analysis is
actually the most predictable type of
trading simply because you are repeating
what price has done to the left
literally all you have to do is look to
the left to know what the right is going
to do patterns repeat themselves every
single day in the market and they will
forever as long as the Candlestick
charts continue to print out Candlestick
charts now if you don't know technical
analysis or you might want a little bit
of clarity on Market structure certain
things about it that's exactly what this
video is about so make sure you watch
the video all the way to the end because
I'm going to give you a full on video on
how to properly read technical analysis
and how I've been doing it for the last
about 6 and 1/2 to 7 years so first
things first on technical analysis is
going going to be the axle Candlestick
chart so this is what you're actually
going to be trading so there's many
different types of charts out there
there's the line chart there's bar
charts and then there is Candlestick
charts now there's plenty of more charts
but I simply have no idea what they are
and honestly you do not need it to be
successful all you need is to know
Candlestick technical analysis chart
which is what I'm going to explain to
you right now in this part right here so
coming over here to trading view this is
what every single person first sees when
they come into the market they see all
of these red lines going down red lines
going up or boxes going down and boxes
going up and at first initial site this
might be very very confusing and it
might be almost overwhelming because you
don't know where you should be looking
at should you be looking at this point
right here to get started off in should
you be looking at this point right here
in order to get started off there's so
many different areas for you to actually
be looking at in this chart that you
don't know where should you be looking
at in order to make money in the market
right because the point of you coming
into this and watching this video and
learning technical analysis is because
you want to make money in the market
well this is what you need to mainly
focus on and that is these technical
analysis patterns on the Candlestick
chart so this chart right here is a
Candlestick chart as you can see right
here these are different types of
technical charts that you can analyze
you can have the bar chart you can have
the line chart you can also have the
Candlestick chart which is the most
famous one and then obviously you have
all of these different types of charts
which I honestly have no idea how to
read and I've never even attempted to at
the end of the day all they do is simply
represent price on real time in front of
your face in a different type of way so
they just represent the market going up
or they represent the market going down
all different types of format but
they're all doing the same exact thing
at the end of the day that is
representing price so you want to make
sure that you read this technical
analysis chart for what it is and the
easiest way to do that is on the line
chart so we're going to be going into
the Candlestick chart a little bit later
into the video but so you guys get the
first initial thought we're going to
start off in the line chart so here in
the line chart it's very straightforward
you have steps going up which is
technical analysis bullish market and
then you have steps going down which is
technical analysis bearish Market
bullish Market are buys bearish Market
or sells and in this perfect example
right here you can see how the market is
having a bearish market to the downside
and then you can see how in this example
right here you can have bullish markets
to the upside so both of these are
technical analy charts so you're
analyzing the charts to determine
whether the market is going to be going
up or whether the market is going to be
going down very simple very
self-explanatory but when you get into
the market and you see this ending point
right here this is where the price is
actually live right now so this is
currently Euro USD which is the most
traded currency in the whole entire
Foreign Exchange Market because it's the
main currencies that are traded which is
the US dollar and the euro dollar so
obviously that makes this pair the most
traded pair in all of the Foreign
Exchange Market so this is where price
is currently right now price is
currently trading at
1.0
8459 which is the last point where it
left off on Market close on Friday so
what you want to determine based off of
this price is what can it do now can it
go to the upside or can it go to the
downside and this is where you would
have to look at the technical analysis
to determine if it's going to go up or
it's going to go down what's going to
make the most sense because at the end
of the day it's going to do either or go
up or down you just have to find an edge
on where it makes most sense to go up
rather than down or go down rather than
up so you do this by reading the
technical analysis so the first things
that you would want to focus on is on
the most recent price which is going to
be this area right here when you're
analyzing technical analysis a lot of
Traders get confused and they want to
start really far back over here or they
want to start off in the middle and you
can do that just to kind of get into the
flow of the market but you want to make
sure you just focus on the last leg of
that because this is where it's going to
determine what the trade is going to do
not what happened 4 months ago or almost
a year ago like that stuff is cool to
know what it did back then but if it's
not relatively close to where price is
right now then it simply doesn't matter
it's just taken away from your time and
taking you away from the focus of what
actually matters into the chart so this
right here is just the line chart so
this is just so you guys can see the
steps going up and the steps going down
but the proper way on how to actually
look at this is on the Candlestick chart
which is going to be this section right
here which is called candlesticks so if
you notice if I go back and forth really
fast from the line chart to the
Candlestick it is the exact same thing
just being represented a different way
and you now know to not be confused
anymore because you now know these steps
going down instead of it being drawn in
a line it's now being drawn in
candlesticks because at the end of the
day you trade candlesticks you can't
trade the line chart it's just not
accurate so this Candlestick chart is
what you are going to be looking at when
analyzing your technical analysis when
you're already on step two step one is
get the feel of the actual line chart
learn what the line chart is going to be
doing get the flow of it understand it
and then you move on to the Candlestick
chart and the simplest analogy that I
can put for this is almost as if you're
learning to ride a bike when you're
first riding a bike you have the
training wheels you just do that so you
make sure that you don't fall to the
side and you get the hang of it after
you're done learning how to ride the
bike you simply take off the training
wheels and you continue to ride the bike
exactly how you're riding it the only
thing that changes is you don't have the
training wheels so you still obviously
have a risk falling but now you're
experienced and that obviously won't
happen so you're still riding the bike
the same exact way nothing changes the
only thing is you have the safety wheels
off same thing here you're analyzing the
market exactly the same as you would
here but now you're removing the safety
of having the line chart and now you're
focusing on the Candlestick chart which
is the real way on how you're going to
be trading and you take off the safety
Wheels on the bike because that is the
real way on how you're going to ride a
bike so this Candlestick chart is formed
by different types of candlesticks so
every single Candlestick as of right now
represents one single dat because I am
currently on the one day time frame so
every single Candlestick is 24 hours so
this right here is a 24-hour Candlestick
every single Candlestick is a 24hour
period and that is what this chart is
made up if I simply change this time
frame from the daily to then the 4 Hour
now every single one of these
candlesticks is going to consist of 4
hours that little cand Candlestick is 4
hours and every single one of these
Candlestick is 4 hours including this
big one right here because this is
currently the 4-Hour time frame and
obviously I could go all the way down to
the 30 minute and every single one of
these candlesticks is a 30 minute time
frame and this is the Simplicity of how
you analyze with the candlesticks now
all we're doing when we're changing time
frames is we're essentially just zooming
in to price so as you can see on the 4
hour if I were to Circle this one single
Candlestick this just looks like I'm
just circling one single Candlestick
which happens every 4 hours because I'm
on the 4H hour time frame but if we were
to go down to let's say the 30 minute
time frame as you can tell I'm actually
catching a lot more than just one single
Candlestick why is that well that is
because all of these little 30 minute
candlesticks because now we are on the
30 minute time frame creates this one
4our Candlestick so every single one of
these 30 minute candlesticks are there
their own situation and all of them
together creates one 4-Hour Candlestick
for example in the 2hour time frame if
you notice these two candlesticks right
here which is going to be these last two
ones right here creates the accumulative
of one Candlestick because it is the
4-Hour Candlestick and obviously this
obviously goes on to the day daily and
the weekly and so on and so forth if I
were to put one big circle around this
big Candlestick and then I go down to
the 4our every single one of these
candlesticks creates that daily
Candlestick so a lot of people don't
understand how to flicker back and forth
from the time frames and how to actually
determine what these Candlestick and
technical analysis is doing all we're
doing is looking at the same exact
Market in just different types of ways
we're looking at it in bigger variables
or in smaller variables but we're
looking at the exact same thing
absolutely nothing changes for example
you right now watching this video you
can be watching this video on your phone
on your computer on your tablet on your
TV or honestly on an Android doesn't
matter you're all looking at the same
video just in different types of ways
some of you guys are looking at on a
bigger screen some of you guys are
looking at on a smaller screen but at
the end of the day it's doing the exact
same thing and that is representing this
video showing you guys the number one
technical analysis video which I'm going
to get later later into it and if you're
watching this on a laptop or on a phone
or something hit the Subscribe button
it's right here or right here doesn't
matter but the point is that when you're
looking at the market like this you are
literally looking at the same thing in
different formats as if you were to be
seeing this video it the same way but in
different formats so now that we
understand what the candlesticks are and
how that consists of technical analysis
because all of these candlesticks
together creates the technical analysis
without these candlesticks together we
will not have technical analysis and we
won't have these patterns that happen
every single time time again that takes
me to the next point which is going to
be trending markets so these Candlestick
patterns they create a pattern with it
and these patterns create Trends Trends
to the upside or Trend to the downside
and the key to trading is trading with
the trend the trend is your friend I
know it might be cringe I know you might
have heard it a million times but it's
what I do every single day and if I were
to not do this every sing single day I
would not be in the successful position
that I am today because going against
the trend is not only hard but it just
does it's it's not going to make you
money and it does not make any sense so
this is what a trending Market is going
to look like because of the Candlestick
patterns that we have identified with
technical analysis so everything right
here is extremely simple and easy to
understand this right here is clearly a
trending Market to the upside what you
want to make sure that you focus on is
at the last point of price right when
you see this right here do not focus on
this point right here do not focus on
anything that is not the last point cuz
once you understand the last point then
you start working backwards once you
understand where the market is right now
now you start looking backwards you're
like okay if this is the high of the
market okay what is this point right
here well this looks like a low and then
this looks like I left a trail
of the market heading to the upside it
is so easy to spot that this Market is
heading to the upside because you
identify where the market is actively
right now and once you understand where
it is actively right now you just follow
its Trail and it's going to literally
tell you what it's doing clearly this
Market is bullish same thing as if we
were to be identifying this Market to
the downside this Market is heading to
the downside it would look something
like this you should only focus at the
lowest points or wherever the market is
actively live and the last point of the
market and you simply just follow the
trail if this is where the market
started you simply follow the trail to
whatever it does and you can clearly see
that it's left you a pattern of the
market heading to the downside this is
how you determine the trend of the
market you need to spot where the market
is actively right now where's the last
point that the market is at and then you
just work backwards because vice versa
if you were to come into the market and
just simply look at it right here you
wouldn't know if to focus on this point
right here you wouldn't know if to focus
on this point right here all of this is
absolutely irrelevant to what is
happening on the live price all the way
over here so if we were to come over
here and identify this point right here
you would identify as your last
structure Point here then you will start
working backwards if you start working
backwards then you can identify what
this Market is clearly doing it's very
simple it's very straight to the point
without this it is going to be very hard
to identify what the trend is doing cuz
in the other way if you were to try and
find something by looking at all of this
information overload you're going to
almost get confused and overwhelmed and
it just honestly kills your trading
motivation and it just deprived you from
what you should be focusing on and that
is where is the market right now do not
focus on where the market was 3 years
ago perfect example is this market right
here if you were to be looking at this
market around here it'd be a little bit
confusing you wouldn't know if it's
upside it's downside but if you were to
look at the last point of where the
market is which is clearly this highest
point right here you simply draw your
little circle here and then you just
start working backwards you start
working from the top to the downside and
you can see that this Market has been
creating higher lows and higher highs to
end up creating this Market to the
upside so this is where the trend is
your friend because after you identify
that this Market is to the upside where
then now you would clearly only be
looking for buys why would you be
looking for sells and if you sometimes
don't have too clear if it's a buy or
it's a sell or you're even a little bit
better at analyzing sells and buys or
buys and sells all you have to do is
simply come here to the section right
click it and then you would invert your
scale and then you completely look at
the markets in the other way and this is
literally showing you the same exact
Market just flipped around it's almost
like if you're watching this video and
you laying down on your bed and you have
the screen sideways you just flip the
screen to the side you're looking at the
same thing you just flipped it same
thing here the same Market but if you
have some type of difficulty identifying
whether the market is to the upside or
the downside or you're only good at
looking at buys or you're only good
looking at sells all you have to do is
just flip the chart so here it's
obviously very clear that this Market is
to the downside because again remember
that we flipped it we would identify
this as our low point and after we
identify it as our low
point we can simply follow the market
and see that it was creating lower lows
and lower highs now this trend is
consisted of lower lows and lower highs
if you're bearish and it's consisted of
higher highs and higher lows if you're
bullish it is absolutely impossible to
have a bullish Market without a higher
low and a higher high and it is
absolutely impossible to have a bearish
market without lower lows and lower
highs let me explain so this right here
is a perfect example of a bullish Market
a bullish Market is consisted of higher
highs and higher lows it is impossible
to have a bullish Market without higher
highs and higher lows and it is
impossible to have a higher high without
a higher low it is impossible you could
only have a higher high if you have a
higher low so make sure you pause the
video and write this down so this right
here is bullish because we are above the
higher low and within the higher high if
this Market were to do something like
this and have a retracement and head to
the upside well now this is the new
higher high within this market so the
higher high gets moved and then the
highest low Point gets moved to the next
highest low point which is this point
right here now this is a perfect example
of a bullish Market the moment this
Market decides to have some type of
retracement into here this point is now
considered a new higher low and a higher
high only because we've broken above the
previous structure point if we did not
break above the previous structure point
we simply do not enter this as a bullish
market so this right here is a higher
high and then the higher low would move
up to the next higher low now this
example right here is not a higher low
why would you count this as a higher low
because it's having a pullback well no
not necessarily this could only be
counted as a higher low once this Market
has created a higher high again remember
it is impossible to have a higher high
without a higher low so if this market
right here did not create a higher high
how would you mark this as the higher
low you're pretty much skipping a step
because this market right now can
clearly do something like this and it
can completely go to the downside
because it hasn't shown you its full
potential yet this Market will remain
bullish
as long as we are above the higher low
and within the higher high meaning this
Market can literally do whatever it
wants it can literally do all of this
right here anything it wants the moment
it breaks above we now have created a
new higher high and the moment it breaks
under we have now had a break of
structure and now this Market is bearish
so this Market can do whatever it wants
in between the higher high and the
higher low and and we are still bullish
the moment we break above this now turns
into the higher high and then this now
turns into the higher low which is going
to be this point right here now the
moment we break under this point now
this Market has completely shifted to
the downside because we have broken
under the higher low so the moment we
body close under this higher low now we
are bearish when we are bearish it is
Mand atories who have a lower low and a
lower high you cannot have a bearish
market without a lower low and a lower
high so what does that make this point
right here well that makes this new low
point a lower low and that makes the
last structure point a lower high now
this Market is bearish now it might look
bullish overall because a beginner
Trader would come into the market and
then it would see something like this
and they'd be like yeah this Market
Market is heading up and that is where
they are completely wrong they're not
paying attention to the market structure
where it is clearly showing you that
this Market is now bearish so now this
Market would then have some type of
retracements and then do something like
this now this is a new lower low and
again it is impossible to have a lower
low without a lower high so that is
where this lower high would then move to
this point right here so again same
thing apply SI as if the market were to
be heading to the upside this Market
could do whatever it wants here go to
the upside to the downside and it mean
nothing the moment we body close Above
This Market we are now bullish and the
moment we body close under this Market
we will continue to become bearish so if
this market closes under this point this
is now the new lower low and then this
is now the new lower high so this Market
can simply do something like like this
and go like this now this Market is no
longer bearish because we have broken
above the lower high making this the new
higher high and then making this point
right here the new higher low it is
impossible to have a bullish Market
without a higher low it is impossible to
have a bearish market without a lower
high write this down the moment we Body
candles they close under a higher low we
are now bearish and the moment we body
Candlestick close above a lower high we
are then bullish this is Major key to
understanding what the trend of the
market is doing so you have extreme
Clarity if the market is bullish or
bearish this way you can determine if
you're interested in buying or if you're
interested in selling so this trend is
identified obviously very simply on the
line chart so I can come into here to
this market and I can simply throw on
the line chart and you can simply
identify well this is clearly the higher
high and after you identify the higher
high then this would be the higher low
very simple very straightforward it's
literally the same thing that we were
just doing but on the actual live
markets but on the line chart so this
would be the higher high and then this
would be the higher low what we would do
is we would anticipate for this to have
a pullback in order for this to head to
the upside if this Market decides to now
break this high higher low now this
Market will be bearish and then this
will be the lower low and then this
would then be the lower high this is
very simple and happens every single day
in the markets across every single time
frame so the way you identify the trend
is exactly the same as you were to do it
on the weekly or the yearly or the 10
year or the 100 year as you would on the
1 hour the 10 minute the 30 minute the 1
minute it's all the same thing because
at the end of the day it's all showing
the same same exact lines the same exact
line chart same exact structure it's all
the same exact thing if you notice that
this right now we are on the weekly time
frame meaning each and every single one
of these candlesticks is one week and
when we were to look at this now on
let's say the 15 minute you can see how
we have an exact same amount of lines
now these lines were obviously looking a
little bit more rigid because the
15-minute moves a lot faster than let's
say the weekly but if I were to hide
what time frame we were on you would
realistically not be able to tell if I
were to zoom in to something like this
because it is simply lines doesn't
matter if it's the Daily doesn't matter
if it's the weekly they all look exactly
the same representing Market structure
to the upside or Market structure to the
downside so this right here is the real
market right so this is this exact
market right here but now on the line
chart and you're going to notice that
every single little sharp edge it's
going to to be a market structure point
it's going to be a potential higher low
it's going to be a potential higher high
so this right here is a prime example of
simple and straight effective Market
structure Market structure is literally
every single point that you are seeing
right here this is Market structure
which is I like to call them an elbow
because it literally looks like an elbow
like it looks like a sharp edge so this
right here would be an elbow which is
Market structure an elbow which is
Market structure and an elbow which is
Market structure and clearly we have
these elbows everywhere throughout the
market so if we go here to the real
Market you can see how we have these
elbows or these Market structure points
everywhere throughout the market you can
see how this right here is your elbow
right here at this point you can see how
we have another elbow at this point we
have literally elbows all throughout the
market structure that this Market is
creating this is a little El elbow
obviously a sharper elbow and then this
is more of a wider elbow so you get all
different types of elbow if you're a fat
guy you're a skinning guy you got
everything that you need here so these
elbows are Market structure and this
Market structure is what creates the
trend of the market it's what creates
the market if it's heading to the upside
it's what creates the market if it's
heading to the downside so when you have
a bullish market like this this is
obviously higher high and then this
would be the the higher low but if you
notice that higher low is a market
structure point it's this the higher low
and then this would be considered the
market structure point and previous
Market structure is this elbow right
here and this elbow right here so
everything that looks like an elbow like
a triangle like a corner like a sharp
edge is Market structure and that helps
determine the trend of the market
whether it's going to the upside side or
whether it's going to the downside I can
literally flip this chart right now and
you can see how it's the same exact
elbows but going to the downside so
everything that we do in trading
whatever you apply to buys is the exact
same thing that applies to sells nothing
changes your Edge is not better on only
buys or your Edge is not only better on
sells it is the exact same pattern the
exact same Market structure the exact
same everything the only thing is that
it flips from one side to the other so
now you understand what the technical
analysis is now you understand what
trend is which is extremely important
you understand Market structure which
Market structure is all of these elbows
and it's honestly what the market is
Crea of because without these elbows
Market would not exist we would simply
have a chart that would look something
like this it would look like a literal
wave and obviously you cannot trade a
wave because it's just not accurate you
would need these sharp edges to
determine when the market is going to go
up or when the market is going to go
down to a lot more more predictable
thank you for the market structure
trading Legends or whoever created this
and that takes me to the next point
which is going to be support and
resistance so support and resistance is
identified because of these elbows
without these elbows you would not be
able to determine what is a level of
support and what is a level of
resistance so again remember what is
support well support is something that
holds something up for example this
table I can use this table as support to
push myself to the upside I'm going to
use this as support and as leverage to
push myself up what is resistance
resistance is something that is holding
you as a ceiling that is pushing you
down let's say I want to use the bottom
of this table as resistance to pull
myself down this is being used as
resistance to pull myself down if you
notice the same table is being used for
support and it is being used for
resistance it the same exact spot being
used for two things because that is
exactly what happens in the market you
can have the same level of supports be
used as resistance in the future or it
have been used as resistance in the past
the support and resistance is consisted
by these Market structure points that
has happened in the market previously in
the past so let me show you so this
right here is a level of support and
resistance oh by the way it's the same
as supply and demand it's the same
as order blocks it's the same
as all these different type of
terminology is all the same support
and resistance is the same thing
everything literally the same thing so
right here you can see how this level of
Market structure which is this elbow
right here is considered a level of
resistance that then in the future was
used as support So this level of
resistance which is a market structure
point was then used as support which now
created a new market structure point
then you have this elbow right here
and this elbow as you can see creates a
level of resistance this level of
resistance is then used in the future as
a level of support it's going to bring
it down for examples purposes and then
this is now a new level of support that
created a new higher high now this is a
new market structure point which is used
as resistance so we can determine that
this can potentially in the near future
have a pullback and use this area as a
support point to then push the market to
the upside where then this would be
creating a support level which is a
level of Market structure so notice how
Market structure is created based off of
support and resistance and support and
resistance is created off of Market
structure they both work together hand
inand in order to create a trending
Market or to create a bearish market now
these level of support and resistance
happen everywhere throughout about the
charts so if we were to come here into
the live markets which is what's going
on here you can see how this live market
you can see how a level of resistance
which is this point right here is then
used as support So this point of
resistance is then used as support you
can then see how this level of supports
is then used as resistance at this point
right here and then you can see how very
easily this level of resistance right
here is then retested and use it as
support So this literally happens Time
and Time and Time Again into the market
and it's a pattern that repeats itself
over and over again I could drag this
same exact spot a little bit more to the
right and you can see how this level was
used as resistance drag a little bit
more to the right you can see how it was
almost used as resistance right here and
this is what Market structure is
consisted of in order to create this
level of support and resistance now keep
in mind that the level of support and
resistance is to be respected about 60
to 75% of the time price doesn't always
have to react off of a support level or
it doesn't always have to react off of a
resistance level it is statistically
proven that it should but you cannot
rely your whole entire strategy just on
that alone you need to have an edge over
the market as a whole but you should
only be buying at a support level or
only be selling at a resistance level
you can have the best Edge in the market
and you can have everything you need to
have in order to take a trade but if you
do not have the area of support to buy
how are you buying like how are you
going to push yourself off off the table
if you're not off the table you can't
like you know I don't know grav I don't
know how to kill gravity or I can't like
levitate myself using mental Force to
just push myself off the table without
physically being touching the table
exact same thing with the markets you
want to only be executing a trade if
you're at that support level if you're
at the table if you're not at the table
simply cannot do anything with it and
obviously same thing happens with
resistance I can't pull myself off of
this table if I'm not physically at the
table so when you're looking for areas
of support and resistance do not pay
attention to the charts do not execute a
trade unless you're actually at the
level of support and resistance so after
you understand how to identify these
levels of Market structuring you learn
how to identify this level of support
and resistance you actually have to
execute this trade on something and the
only way for you to execute it is on the
actual Candlestick patterns because the
line chart again it's just for a very
beginner section it's just for you to
understand how to read the market but
you can't trade off of the chart so this
is where you would have to go find your
Candlestick pattern in order to execute
the trade so this is where you would
then obviously flip over to the
Candlestick pattern and I'm going to
teach you the most powerful and most
effective Candlestick pattern that I use
every single day but after you hit the
Subscribe button you got to do it I know
you haven't done it I can tell that's
why you're doing it here again just hit
the Subscribe button and then we can
carry on I'll give you a second go ahead
all right perfect so now that you
subscribe this is what the perfect
Candlestick pattern is it's what I use
every single day if I don't have this I
do not enter the trade that is going to
be drum roll a bullish engulfing
Candlestick for buys or a bearish
engulfing Candlestick for sells I know
you might have heard me say in the past
but it is as repetitive and as redundant
as it is it simply works and I do not
have to change anything of my trading
strategy and when it comes to technical
analysis there's nothing you need to
change in order to properly Iden Iden
ify the market correctly the only way
you can confirm that something is going
in One Direction versus the other is if
you have momentum how do you identify
the momentum well if price is engulfing
the previous price if price is engulfing
the previous price it is clearly showing
action of strength and is clearly
showing that it is dominating that
market so that is your entry
confirmation that you're looking for in
order to enter the trade for example if
you were to identify in a race who is
winning well you're going to identify
that the person that is engulfing the
other car and beating them by a lot is
winning you're want to bet on that guy
well same thing in the market you want
to bet on the Candlestick that is
winning the Candlestick that is
engulfing that's eating the last couple
of candlesticks and the only way that
you can bet is when you know that that
is happening imagine you can bet on a
race when you already see who's winning
odds of you making a lot of more money
are literally right in front of your
face because the winner is already ahead
so you just bet on the winner it's the
same exact thing here in the market once
the market creates that bullish
engulfing Candlestick it's the winner
already getting ahead that is your
confirmation that you can then get into
the market it's showing you who is
winning so you go with the winner now if
you bet before that you're taking a bit
of a risk because obviously you don't
know if there's a pretty much lock that
the trade is actually going to go into
that direction it could be a better
entry and you can have better odds but
the probabilities are not so much in
your favor as if you were to already see
who is winning the race
and this Candlestick pattern is actually
one of not only the most powerful but
the most simplest because there is
hundreds of different types of
candlesticks and these are all different
types of indications when to enter the
trade when to avoid a trade but this is
specifically when to enter a trade so
let me actually show you what this looks
like so this right here would be a
perfect example of a bullish engulfing
Candlestick pattern which is this right
here so you can see how this blue
Candlestick has engulfed the last one
two candlesticks confirming that this
direction is now going to head to the
upside you can also see how this
humongous red Candlestick is engulfing
the last 1 two 3 4 five almost six
candlesticks confirming that the market
is now going to head to the downside you
can see how this Candlestick right here
has engulfed the last one two almost
three candlesticks and again keep in
mind currently we are on the daily time
frame meaning that this one single day
has eaten the last 3 days that should
give you indication that there is a lot
of sellers into the market that you
should be interested in trading picture
as if there's a race and there is a 3
day ahead race that one imagine that the
cars are racing for weeks at a time and
there's this one car that has now
skipped Everybody by 3 days it has 3
days ahead of all the three other cars
doesn't it make more sense to bet on
that guy that is ahead versus the guys
that are behind well that is the
possibility that the market is giving
you by entering a trade after it already
shows you its hand with this engulfing
confirmation now you have to be very
patient in order to wait for this to
happen and this is where a lot of
Traders mess up because they don't want
to be patient but at the end of the day
patience pays and if you don't have the
patience you simply are not meant for
this sorry it sucks but if you don't
follow the rules of trading you will not
succeed it is as simple as that because
why should you succeed if you're not
being patient rather I have to be
patient to then get the same success
it's simply not fair and it's just not
how the markets work you have to follow
the rules in order to get the reward you
can also see a perfect example of this
engulfing Candlestick right here so you
can see how this engulfing Candlestick
engulf the last one two three four
candlesticks this right here is not an
engulfing Candlestick as you can see see
this little Candlestick did not eat the
last Red Candlestick so it does not make
it an engulfing Candlestick you can tell
how this red Candlestick is not an
engulfing Candlestick this is an
engulfing Candlestick because it ate the
last several of candlesticks this right
here is not an engulfing Candlestick
this little blue one because it did not
eat the last one or two candlesticks so
an engulfing Candlestick is when it eats
a minimum of one Candlestick to the left
of it whether it is to the upside or it
is to the downside without this it is
not an engulfing
Candlestick this right here is a perfect
example of a beautiful strong bullish
engulfing Candlestick which it has eaten
the last 1 2 3 4 5 6 seven candlesticks
in one single day so this Candlestick is
7 days ahead of everybody else obviously
you can then see how the market followed
to the upside and that confirmed that
that was going to be the winning trade
the winning car in the race and this
applies this Candlestick applies to any
single time frame doesn't matter if
you're on The Daily doesn't matter if
you're on the 1 hour as long as you have
your engulfing Candlestick the market is
destined to go into that favor because
the market is showing their hand first
doesn't matter if you're betting on car
races or if you're reading on RC car
races there at the end of the day
whoever is ahead has the Le lead simply
makes more sense to bet on that person
versus the person that is not so now all
of these candlesticks together they
create patterns obviously you can see
the same pattern heading to the upside
you can see the same patterns heading to
the downside that takes me to my next
point which is going to be Candlestick
patterns that the market shows you and
now these patterns are almost like
where's Waldo as soon as you find Waldo
in the map of where he would be you
almost can't unsee it like it's actually
impossible once you spotted him you
spotted him and that's it there's no
going back you know where he's at same
thing happens here once you spot these
patterns of the market you can't unsee
it like it's literally right in front of
your face and it's going to be there
permanently now every single time and
I'm literally about to crack something
for you guys that you probably did not
know that you had and that you were
missing out by not properly identifying
the markets the way you should now this
Market that you see right in front of
you here not only are we on the line
chart just to make this very simple for
introduction but there is two different
different types of Candlestick patterns
in this section right here you have a
head and shoulders pattern and a
inverted Head and Shoulders pattern and
it might not be so obvious right now but
as soon as I spot it out you're going to
have an aha moment and it's going to be
like where's Waldo you're going to it's
going to be impossible to unsee what
you're about to see so this market right
here actively right now the first thing
that you have to do always is focus on
the first things first which is where is
the market right now where is price and
price is at that very point right there
so then this is where you would start
working your way down you would start
working from this point to this point to
this point to Etc so you would identify
that this Market is obviously bullish
it's creating higher highs and it's
creating higher lows so this Market is a
bullish market now this bullish Market
was created because of a pattern now
what pattern you may be asking well just
to make it very simple and straight to
the point
it is going to be a inverted Head and
Shoulders pattern which is going to be
this pattern down at this point right
here so it's an inverted Head and
Shoulders pattern which is an opposite
of a head and shoulders pattern inverted
Head and Shoulders patterns usually
happen at the bottom of a trend as a
reversal and then head and shoulders
happen at the top of a trend as a
reversal from the point there so these
patterns are used as reversal patterns
so this is an inverted Head and
Shoulders pattern which happened at the
bottom of the trend to then shift this
Market to the upside and then if you
notice this add a little bit more to the
left would be a fullblown head and
shoulders pattern to then creates a
reversal for then the market to the
downside so you can see how this head
and shoulders pattern then created a
bearish market and then you can see how
this head and shoulders then created a
bullish Market this is because these
reversal patterns are happening at the
highs and at the lows of the market as
reversal patterns it is the stronger
pattern that you can possibly see in the
market and it is almost so obvious that
once you see it you can't unsee it it's
very obvious that this is a left
shoulder that this is a head and that
then this point right here is another
right shoulder now it is impossible to
have a head and shoulders pattern
without a left shoulder a head and a
right shoulder confirming that it's
broken through the neckline now a lot of
people might believe that this right
here could potentially be or is a head
and shoulders pattern this right here is
not a head and shoulders pattern because
this can literally just do this and then
what where did your head and shoulders
patterns go well nowhere clearly it
never existed a head and shoulders
pattern only exists once it has broken
and firmed the neckline of the head and
shoulders so this is going to be the
neckline at this point right here which
is what's held up by a level of support
so the support is the neckline of The
Head and Shoulders that is created of
what these elbow points which is going
to be these Market structure points
right here which are going to be held up
by this support so the only way you have
a confirmation of a head and shoulders
is once we break through that neckline
line of the head and shoulders and
obviously the same exact thing applies
when you have a inverted Head and
Shoulders the only thing that changes is
that it's simply the other way this
right here is it a head and shoulders
I'm going to let you think for a second
go ahead I'm going to drink water
thinkk no this is not a head and
shoulders pattern why because this can
literally just do this right here and
then where did your head and shoulders
patterns go nowhere it never existed why
because it never broke through this
neckline right here if it looks a little
bit confusing all you have to do is flip
this chart to the other side and then
you can clearly see that it never broke
through the neckline never making it a
valid Head and Shoulders pattern so you
notice it's exact same thing just
flipping it to the downside because this
is a inverted Head and Shoulders which
happens at the bottom of a trend so this
right here is not a head and shoulders
pattern if this would have done this
then we have a confirmed inverted Head
and Shoulders pattern that now we can be
interested in taking this to the upside
because now the market has then shifted
so this literally happens Time and Time
and Time Again into the markets every
single day like to the point where right
now as I'm skimming through this Market
I seeing tens of different Head and
Shoulders patterns now again keep in
mind these Head and Shoulders patterns
are not always going to be very pretty
not always going to look like something
like this you know it could happen but
that possibility of that is not very
high you're going to sometimes have a
little ugly head and shoulders it's
nothing wrong with a little ugly head
and shoulders like you know we've all
been with an ugly person it's not a big
deal do it for the game it's part of
what it is sometimes you would have
something that looks like this but it's
a valid Head and Shoulders pattern you
would have something like this and then
it would look like this it's ugly but it
is what it is is it's a head and
shoulders pattern you just want to make
sure that you can identify that it is a
left ahead and then a right shoulder to
confirm that it is a head and shoulders
pattern this right here is a perfect
example of an ugly head and shoulders
pattern this is a left head and then a
ugly right shoulder which then creates
The Head and Shoulders pattern clearly
happened at the top of the market which
then created the move to the downside
and these obviously also happened in any
single time frame of the market and it's
going to happen every single day that
the market has different opportunities
for you to trade on any single time
frame now there's obviously many
different types of patterns and I have a
whole entire video right here that
explains to you the patterns that I use
in my strategy every single day that
give me the best Edge over the market
because just like the head and shoulders
pattern and they happen every single day
in the market there's there's two
different other patterns that I
personally use but I explain into more
detail in this video right here so make
sure you go check it out and this is all
just a very simple way of how to read
technical analysis and different types
of patterns that you can identify when
reading the market and this is all very
surface level ways on how to actually
see different technical ways on how to
read it because technical analysis
trading is simply the most successful
route that retail Traders have taken
over the last decades in order to
succeed and it's what I've been using
for the last 6 to 7 years along with all
of my students that let to make anywhere
from $1,000 to
$11,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader now if you don't know what
set and forget is or it's your first
time hearing it make sure you click the
link in the description below because I
have a video there for you that explains
to you exactly what it is and I show you
how to identify these patterns and
create an edge over the market that's
going to make you anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader so if you want to know
what Center foret is and what it's all
about and how it lets students have
results like these or even these click
the link in the description below for
you and you're going to be able to see
what it's all about and you're going to
get on a call with me every single week
identifying these markets every single
week seeing what makes the most sense
does it make more sense to buy or does
it make more sense to sell because I
share my personal trades with my
students every single Sunday on a call
that we get on before the market starts
so we can actually see what markets are
having the best patterns and the best
tech technical analysis so if you want
to make anywhere from $1,000 to $1,500 a
week and be part of my set and forget
Community make sure you hit the link in
the description below and I'll see you
inside appreciate you guys watching this
video all the way to the end hit that
like And subscribe button and I'll see
you guys the next video